<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Application2.1</string>

    <string name="article_title">Cats</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">Amazing facts about cats</string>
    <string name="article">Outdoor intact (Tom Cats) males cover 3 to 5 miles of their trails of previously marked territory.  Daily rounds assure the cat that his turf is well scented
10 million more cats are kept as pets than dogs
Every cat carries the Tabby gene
Most adult cats lack the enzymes necessary to digest milk
Most of a kitten’s growth takes place during sleep
As a kitten matures, its 26 milk teeth are replaced by 30 permanent teeth
The kitten’s permanent teeth grow in between the ages of 12 to 18 weeks
The hunting instinct is buried deeply in the mind of even the youngest kittens.  Rather than just eat its food, a kitten visually examines it and will paw at it, as it would an animal brought back from the hunt, to check if it is safe to approach
Cats are most active in the morning and evening (dawn and twilight)—the prime hunting hours
After a successful hunt for mice or a toy, many cats engage in a tension releasing dance. It builds the cats self-esteem and confidence
Cats prefer foods at body temperature—the temperature of freshly killed prey
While hunting the whiskers can reach forward to give information about the prey they stalk
The cat’s whiskers have developed into antennae and help detect movement nearby
A cat’s sensitive whiskers can detect even slight changes in air pressure and air currents—giving the cat “radar” at night, or insight of a storm about to come
Cats are either right- or left-pawed (handed), showing a distinct preference for one paw over the other
When cats purr, it is an expression of intense emotion, meaning pleasure or pain
The domestic cat is the only feline that can hold its tail in a vertical position while walking, wild cats must hold the tail horizontally or tucked between their legs
Cats, Camels and Giraffes walk with 2 right and 2 left legs</string>

    <string name="article_title1">Dogs</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle1">Amazing facts about Dogs</string>
    <string name="article1">Your dog is as smart as a 2-year-old toddler.
There’s a reason your tot and your pup get along so well: they speak the same language. Or at least, they likely understand roughly the same number of words and gestures — 250!

Dogs and cats both slurp water the same way.
This may be hard to believe since dogs are such messy drinkers, but just like cats, our canine friends bend the tip of their tongue and raise liquid in a column up to their mouths.

Your dog does have a sense of time — and misses you when you’re gone.
If you think your dog knows when it’s time for dinner or a walk, you’re right! Dogs pick up on our routines and habits, and they also sense how much time has passed. One study showed how dogs responded differently to their owners being gone for different lengths of time.

Your dog’s whiskers help him “see” in the dark.
Okay, it’s not quite night-vision or a super power, but those whiskers pick up on even subtle changes in air currents, providing your pup with information about the size, shape, and speed of things nearby. This allows your dog to better sense approaching dangers or prey — even at night.

Dogs only have sweat glands in their paws.
More specifically, they are found between their paw pads. That’s why it can help to wet the bottom of their feet on a hot day, and it’s also why dogs rely on panting as a means of cooling down.

On average, a dog’s mouth exerts 320 pounds of pressure.
The tests were done on a German shepherd, American pit bull terrier, and Rottweiler. In comparison, human beings exert 120 pounds, white sharks exert 600 pounds, and crocodiles exert a whopping 2,500 pounds! Dogs also have ten more adult teeth than humans — 42 versus 32.

Your one year-old pup is as physically mature as a 15-year-old human.
Of course, different breeds age a little differently. Large dogs age faster than small ones. You can get a more exact comparison for your dog using this nifty Dog Age Calculator.

Your dog’s sense of smell is 1,000 to 10 million times better than yours.
Depending on the breed, your dog has between 125 million to 300 million scent glands — compared to only 5 million for humans. And the part of your dog’s brain that controls smell is 40 times larger than yours — that’s true, even though the canine brain is much smaller than the human, relative to size. A human’s brain is about 1/40th of their body weight while a dog’s brain is only 1/125th. Don’t feel too smug, though — an ant’s brain is 1/7th its body weight.

Dogs can hear 4 times as far as humans.
Puppies may be born deaf, but they quickly surpass our hearing abilities. Dogs can also hear higher pitched sounds, detecting a frequency range of 67 to 45,000 hertz (cycles per second). The human range is from 64 to 23,000 hertz. In both dogs and humans, the upper end of hearing range decreases with age.

Your dog can smell your feelings.
Your pup can pick up on subtle changes in your scent, which can help him figure out how you are feeling — such as by smelling your perspiration when you become nervous or fearful. It’s also likely how dogs can detect certain diseases or know that a household member is pregnant.</string>

    <string name="article_title2">Pets</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle2">Amazing facts about Pets</string>
    <string name="article2">Did you know that rats breed so fast that in about 18 months, two rats could have created a colony of one million rats? Of course, due to natural selection, most of them do not survive.
        Or else, we would have to find a pied piper! The blue whale’s cry is so loud (about 188 decibels) and can be detected about 800 kilometers away.
        Did you know that both cows and horses can sleep standing up? Another interesting fact is the tentacles of the Giant Arctic Jellyfish measure to about 36 meters in length.
        The sharks’ skeleton is made entirely from cartilage and not bones, and that the biggest eggs in the world are laid by the sharks.
        Another interesting fact - the rhinoceros’ horn is made from compacted hair instead of bone or melanin or other substance.
        Did you know that the sheep’s’ stomach is made up of four chambers and each one is used to help them digest the food they eat?
        The polar bear’s skin is actually black, despite its white, fluffy fur.
        The Tasmanian Devil is the largest carnivorous marsupial in the world, and is only found in the wild in Tasmania, Australia.
        Did you know that the housefly’s lifespan is for only two to three weeks?
        Did you know that it is only the female mosquito that bites humans?
        We are sure that your kids will enjoy these fun facts about animals. Visit us every week for more amusing facts. Enjoy.
        Cats have an average life span of about 12 to 15 years.
        While a male cat is called a tom, a female cat is mostly called a molly or queen.
        The young ones are referred to as kittens, and a colony of cats is called a clowder.
        Domestic cats are much lighter than their mighty cousins are and weigh only about 4 kilograms to 5 kilograms.
        The heaviest domestic cat that is on record weighs about 22 kilograms.
        Cats have excellent hearing as well as a strong sense of smell.
        They sleep for over 14 hours a day thereby conserving energy.
        They also have powerful night vision that allows to see six times more than what a human can see at night.
        The cats use their whiskers to measure whether a space is too small for them to crawl through.
        Cats are also one of the cleanest pets and spend a large time licking and cleaning themselves.
        Cats have teeth and bodies adapted for hunting small animals such as mice, squirrels, rats, and small birds.
        They are lethal hunters and are very similar to their larger cousins.
        It is impossible for the prey to know when a cat is sneaking upon them, because it keeps noise to a minimum with absolutely no tracks.</string>
</resources>
